# **Kaspars Mazurs**

## **Junior Full Stack Developer**

<u>Kaspars.mazurs@gmail.com</u> • +353 83 098 1613 • Ireland <u>GitHub</u> • <u>linkedin</u>

#### **Executive Summary**

Junior Software Developer studying for a Diploma in Full-stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. I have more than 15 years of experience in sales and product management. I am a valuable team player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving abilities. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can grow and contribute!

### **Education**

July 2021–August 2022 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland -

(Credit Rated by the University of West of Scotland)

2019 – 2021 Professional Master's Degree in Business Administration (Prof.Mg.MBA)

Business University "Turība", Latvia

2015 – 2019 Professional Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration

Business University "Turība", Latvia

2008 – 2011 Computer Science

Riga Technical College, Latvia

2003 – 2007 Computer Systems Technician

Ogre Professional High School, Latvia

#### **Technical Skillset**

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Version Control: Git, Github
Frameworks: Bootstrap

#### <u>Technical Skillset</u> (Still to learn in the Code institute curriculum)

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks: Django, jQuery

#### Portfolio projects

1. Battlefield duel - Battlefield duel is a landing page for a game in, which your main task is to win the opponent in a shooting duel.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS, JavaScript,.

GitHub - <a href="https://github.com/KasparsMazurs/battlefield\_duel">https://github.com/KasparsMazurs/battlefield\_duel</a> Live Site - <a href="https://kasparsmazurs.github.io/battlefield\_duel/">https://kasparsmazurs.github.io/battlefield\_duel/</a> 2. **Mr\_kris\_tattoo** - Mr. Kris Tattoo is a landing page for a self-made artist specializing in digital art and tattoos.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS.

GitHub - https://github.com/KasparsMazurs/mr\_kris\_tattoo

Live Site - https://kasparsmazurs.github.io/mr\_kris\_tattoo/

3. Interactive story - Interactive story is a Python terminal game.

**Technologies Used** - Python.

GitHub - https://github.com/KasparsMazurs/Storry

Live Site - <a href="https://interactivestory.herokuapp.com/">https://interactivestory.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### **Work Experience**

February 2022–Present

Sales representative

Tempside Ltd., Dublin, Ireland

- Build and maintain strong, long-lasting client relationships
- Develop new business with existing clients and/or identify areas of improvement to meet sales quotas
- Identify new business opportunities by finding potential customers

July 2021–January 2022

**Moving to Ireland** 

January 2021–June 2021

**Senior Product Manager** 

Latakko, Riga, Latvia

- Through various market activities, the Q2 profit plan was not only reached, but also even exceeded by 40%
- I was leading the company's reorganization process of transitioning 3 departments (pricing, product, and procurement departments) into one department and under my supervision
- I was able to increase the influence of categories under my supervision impact on the company's total revenue from 60% to 65% in 6 months
- Supervise and support Product Managers and coordinate cross-functional teams
- Prepare budgets, allocate resources, and delegate tasks
- Prepare recommendations to track product use and impact on end-users

*July 2019–December 2020* 

**Product Group Manager** 

Eugesta, Riga, Latvia

- I was responsible for launching two new brands in the market (Love, Beauty&Planet; Seven Generation). My responsibility was the whole new brand launch process, which included: market research, setting strategic goals, pricing, etc.,
- I managed to establish and open a completely new sales channel for one of the new brands
- I participated in the development of category settings for the biggest portfolio category of the company
- Define the product vision, strategy, and roadmap
- Develop project plans, budgets, and schedules, based on the client's demands
- Gather, manage and prioritize market & customer demands

January 2018–June 2019

**Key Account Manager** 

Eugesta, Riga, Latvia

- I managed to develop one of the channels entrusted to me by 45%, and after that, this channel became the biggest contributor to my portfolio
- I ensured that the new product launch in my client's retail chain was reached by 90% in 2 weeks' time, and in 3 weeks' time the product was launched in 100% client's stores
- I made a cooperation agreement with a completely new client in the channel given to me. After 2 months this client contributed 20% of the total revenue in my portfolio

- Develop trustful relationships with a portfolio of major clients to ensure they do not turn to competitors
- Supervise the account teams assigned to each key client
- Ensure the correct products and services are delivered to customers in a timely manner

December 2015–December 2017 Export Sales Manager
Ilgezeem Ltd, Riga, Latvia

- I was successful in launching products in such countries as Finland, Russia, Hong Kong, China, Maldives, United Arab Emirates, etc.,
- My responsibility was to lead the process of obtaining a HALAL certificate, which allowed me to sell the company's products in Arabic countries
- I was the Lead Representative in the biggest industries exhibitions in Russia, Germany, etc.,
- Identify new business opportunities by finding potential customers from different countries
- Plan, design, develop and implement different sales activities by researching the customer's needs and demands
- Negotiate and monitor export rates and services to reduce operating costs and increase profitability

January 2014–November 2015 Key Account Manager

Latvijas Mobilais Telefons, Riga, Latvia

September 2011–December 2013 Operational Manager of Customer Center

LMT Retail & Logistics Ltd, Riga, Latvia

December 2007–August 2011 Customer Consultant

LMT Retail & Logistics Ltd, Riga, Latvia

#### **Additional Information**

- Native Latvian, Fluent English, Fluent Russian.
- Driving License
- Soft skills:
  - o Analytical,
  - o Problem-solving,
  - o Team Management,
  - o Time Management,
  - o Communication.